coserv.com 2013-09-07

# Privacy Policy

CoServ is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience and reliable energy services. This Privacy Statement applies to the CoServ Web site and meters on CoServ’s electric and gas distribution systems, including data-transmitting electronic meters on CoServ’s electric system (“CoServ advanced meters”), and governs data collection and usage. By using the CoServ Web site and/or accepting electricity through a CoServ advanced meter or natural gas through a CoServ natural gas meter, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of your Personal Information**  
CoServ collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, date of birth, taxpayer identification number, driver’s license number, home or work address, or telephone number. CoServ also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by CoServ. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by CoServ for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the CoServ Web site.

**CoServ Advanced Meter Information**  
CoServ advanced meters collect customer data, including electricity usage data.  CoServ protects CoServ advanced meter customer data in the same manner that it protects other personal information that it collects. In particular, except under the limited circumstances discussed above, CoServ does not release your CoServ advanced meter customer data to any other person or business entity without your affirmative consent.

**Use of your Personal Information**  
CoServ collects and uses your personal information to operate the CoServ Web site and CoServ advanced meters, and deliver the services you have requested. CoServ also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from CoServ and its affiliates. CoServ may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

CoServ does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. CoServ may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (i.e., e-mail address, name, home or business address, telephone number, energy usage) is not transferred to the third party.  In addition, CoServ may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you e-mail or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to CoServ, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

CoServ does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

CoServ keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within CoServ, in order to determine what CoServ services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within CoServ to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through CoServ public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: CoServ does not read any of your private online communications.

CoServ encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from the CoServ Web site so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. CoServ is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the CoServ family of Web sites.

CoServ may disclose your personal information collected on the CoServ Web site or through CoServ advanced meters, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on CoServ or the CoServ Web site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of CoServ; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of CoServ, or the public.

**Use of Cookies**  
The CoServ Web site uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize CoServ pages, or register with the CoServ Web site or services, a cookie helps CoServ to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same CoServ Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the CoServ features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the CoServ services or Web sites you visit.

**Security of your Personal Information**  
CoServ secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. CoServ secures the personally identifiable information from CoServ advanced meters and you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

**Changes to this Statement**  
CoServ will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. CoServ encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of how CoServ is protecting your information.

**Contact Information**  
CoServ welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you believe that CoServ has not adhered to this Privacy Statement, please contact CoServ at [contact@coserv.com](mailto:contact@coserv.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy any problem.
